Herz, John H.; Papers ger015
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
John H. Herz Papers
1917-2005
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
ger015
31 cubic ft.
The John H. Herz Papers consist of documents and autobiographical materials, professional and personal correspondence, copies of Herz's published and unpublished writings, texts of numerous speeches and lectures, teaching materials, as well as Herz's research collections on topics relating to his writings and lectures.
Biographical Sketch
John H. Herz was born as Hans Herz in Düsseldorf, Germany to Carl and Elizabeth Aschaffenburg Herz on September 23, 1908. Herz received his grammar school and high school education in Düsseldorf and graduated from the Städtisches Realgymnasium zu Düsseldorf in 1927. Herz continued his studies at the Universities at Freiburg im Breisgau, Heidelberg, Berlin and Cologne, and graduated with a degree in public law from the University of Cologne in 1931 under the direction of Hans Kelsen. From 1931 to 1933, Herz served in the courts of Düsseldorf as Gerichtsreferendar (clerk), until the Nazi racist laws forced his dismissal in 1933. Even after his dismissal in 1933, Herz continued to work as an attorney's assistant to a private firm in Düsseldorf until 1935, when he was able to immigrate to Switzerland under a student visa. For the next three years, Herz worked as a translator for the International Labour Office in Geneva, while at the same time attending the Institut Universitaire de Hautes Études Internationales. Herz received a "diplôme" from the institute in 1938 with a thesis entitled The National Socialist Doctrine of International Law and published in the same year under the pseudonym Eduard Bristler.
In 1938, Herz emigrated to the U.S. and began his U.S. career as John H. Herz at the Institute of Advanced Studies in Princeton, New Jersey, where he remained for the next three years. In 1941, he married Anne Klein and accepted a position as an Instructor in Government at Howard University in Washington, D.C., where he remained until 1952. During his years in Washington, Herz became an American citizen in 1944 and also served as a political analyst in the Central European Section of the Office of Strategic Services and for the U.S. Intelligence and Research Office of the Department of State, as well as continuing to write and publish in the fields of political science and international politics. In 1951, Herz received the Woodrow Wilson Foundation Book Award for his publication, Political Realism and Political Idealism, and in 1952, with co-editor Gwendolen Carter, published the first edition of the textbook, Major Foreign Powers, which was reprinted 5 additional times (1952, 1957, 1962, 1967 and 1972).
In 1952, John Herz accepted a position as Associate Professor in the Department of Political Science at the City College of the City University of New York, where he remained until his retirement at the rank of Full Professor in 1977. During his years at City College, Herz served as Chairman for the Masters Program in International Relations (1953-1977) and also accepted Visiting Professorships at Columbia University, the Graduate Faculty of the New School for Social Research, the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy of Tufts University, the Freie Universität Berlin and the University of Marburg. In addition to his ambitious teaching career, Herz continued his association with Gwendolen Carter and together they published three additional works, which became standard textbooks in U.S. universities: Government and Politics in the Twentieth Century (1961), Documents of Major Foreign Powers (1968) and German Constitutional Documents Since 1871 (1970).
After his retirement in 1977 with the title of Professor Emeritus, Herz became a member of the Center for European Studies at the Graduate Center of the City University of New York and continued to publish books, articles and lecture in the area of political theory and government. In 1984, Herz completed his autobiography, which was published in German as Vom Überleben. Wie ein Weltbild entstand.
John Herz died on December 26, 2005 in Scarsdale, New York.
1908 Born September 23 in Düsseldorf as Hans Herz, son of Carl (a judge) and Elizabeth Aschaffenburg Herz.
1915-1927 Attended grade school and high school (Gymnasium).
1927-1931 Attended universities in Freiburg im Breisgau, Heidelberg, Berlin and Cologne.
1931 Awarded Dr. jur. from the University of Cologne, with a dissertation under the direction of Hans Kelsen, Die Identität des Staates, published in Düsseldorf in 1931.
1931-1933 Served as Gerichtsreferendar in the courts in Düsseldorf until he was dismissed under racist Nazi legislation in 1933.
1933-1935 Worked as attorney's assistant (Wenderoth) in Düsseldorf.
1935 Emigrated to Switzerland on student visa.
1935-1938 Attended Graduate Institute of International Studies (Institut de Hautes Études Internationales) in Geneva, Switzerland; received a diploma with a thesis on The National Socialist Doctrine of International Law (Die Völkerrechtslehre des Nationalsozialismus), which he published under the pseudonym Eduard Bristler; worked concurrently as a translator for the International Labour Office in Geneva.
1938 Emigrated to the United States.
1938-1941 Member of the Institute of Advanced Study, Princeton University.
1940 Summer Instructor at Trinity College, Hartford, CT, in the Department of History and Political Science.
1941 June 22 Married Anne Klein.
1941-1952 Professor, Department of Government, Howard University, Washington, D.C.
1943-1945 Served as a political analyst in the Central European Section of the Office of Strategic Services, Washington, D.C.
1944 Became U.S. citizen.
1945 Aide to U.S. Prosecutor for Nazi Criminality at Nuremberg, Germany.
1946 Birth of son, Stephen.
1946-1948 Political analyst for the Intelligence and Research Office, U.S. Department of State.
1951 Awarded Woodrow Wilson Foundation Book Award for Political Realism and Political Idealism.
1952-1977 Associate professor then full professor, Department of Political Science, City College of the City University of New York (teaching courses in international politics, political theory, comparative politics).
1953 Summer, consultant to RAND Corporation to conduct a study of the political attitudes of the West German civil service and judiciary.
1953-1954 Rockefeller Foundation fellowship.
1953-1977 Chairman, Masters Program in International Relations, City College.
1953-1968 Visiting Professorships at Columbia University (1957, 1966); New School for Social Research, Graduate Faculty (1953, 1958); Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy, Tufts University (1963); Freie Universität Berlin (1960); Universität Marburg (1968).
1960 Fulbright teaching fellowship to teach at Freie Universität Berlin.
1963-1964 Rockefeller Foundation fellowship.
1974 Awarded the Verdienstkreuz 1. Klasse by the West German government on October 24.
1977 Retirement; granted status of Professor Emeritus; member of the Center for European Studies at the Graduate Center of the City University of New York.
1981 Carl von Ossietzky Professor at Freie Universität Berlin.
1984 Publication of autobiography in German, Vom Überleben. Wie ein Weltbild entstand.
2003 Death of wife, Anne Klein Herz.
2005 Died on December 26 in Scarsdale, New York.
Scope and Contents
The John H. Herz Papers consist of 31 cubic feet of materials. The collection includes documents and autobiographical materials (including his autobiography Vom Überleben), professional and personal correspondence, copies of his published and unpublished writings (manuscripts, typescripts, reprints and books), texts of numerous speeches and lectures (published and unpublished), teaching materials, as well as Herz's research collections on topics relating to his writings and lectures. The collection contains a nearly complete collection of Herz's writings spanning six decades from his early years in Germany and Switzerland to his later years in the United States after his forced emigration in 1938.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized as follows:
Series 1: Biographical & autobiographical materials, 1918-2005
Series 2: General correspondence, 1938-2005
Series 3: Correspondence with publishers, co-editors, contributors to volumes, 1949-1995
Series 4: Organizations & institutions: correspondence, minutes, publications, newsletters, 1943-2002
Series 5: Manuscripts, typescripts, proofs of monographs, textbooks, 1952-1982
Series 6: Essayistic writings, poetry, short prose, 1930-2005
Series 7: Texts of lectures, conference materials; course notes & lectures
Series 8: Publications by colleagues, other scholars
Series 9: Political pamphlets
Series 10: Research materials, 1944-1994
Series 11: Audio and video tapes
Acquisition Information
The bulk of the materials in the collection were donated by John H. Herz in March 1980. Additional materials were added to the collection by Herz up until and immediately following Herz's death in 2005. In 2022, Steven Fischler, who produced a documentary featuring Herz and other Jewish refugee academics who taught at historically Black colleges and universities, donated a small amount of material.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Political Science; World War, 1939-1945--Refugees.; Lecture notes; Manuscripts; Correspondence; Speeches; Herz, John H., 1908-2005.; Carter, Gwendolen Margaret, 1906-1991.; Holborn, Louise W. (Louise Wilhelmine), 1898-.; United Nations. Commission to Study the Organization of Peace
- Biographical & autobiographical materials, 1918-2005; 1; 70 file folders + oversized documents
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains some documents from Herz's early years in Düsseldorf, includes notebooks from his university courses in Freiburg im Breisgau, Berlin and Heidelberg, as well as documents from his years in Geneva, Switzerland (1935-1938). A large portion of this series is devoted to Herz's autobiographical writings, including travelogues, interviews of Herz by others, and several versions of his autobiography, published in German in 1984 as Vom Überleben. Wie mein Weltbild entstand, and the unpublished English version, On Human Survival.
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Diary, 1918 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 1)
  - Notebooks. Hindenburgschule, Städtisches Gymnasium und Realgymnasium, 1925-1926 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 2)
  - Notebooks. Albert-Ludwigs-Universität Freiburg i.Br, 1927 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 3)
  - Notebooks. Universität Heidelberg, 1928 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 4)
  - Notebooks, Friedrich-Wilhelms-Universität zu Berlin, 1928-1929 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 5)
  - Notebooks, Universität Köln, 1929 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 6)
  - Letters of reference, 1933-1938 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 7)
  - Work contracts, International Labour Office, League of Nations, Geneva, 1935-1938 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 8)
  - Notebooks, Institut Universitaire de Hautes Études Internationales, Geneva, 1935-1936 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 9)
  - Certificates, Institut Universitaire de Hautes Études Internationales, Geneva, 1937-1938 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 10)
  - Applications for positions, grants, 1937-1952 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 11)
  - Documents relating to property at Goethestrasse 29, Düsseldorf, 1938-1950 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 12)
  - Herz' Statement of Work and Activities in OSS, 1943-1944 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 13)
  - Restitution Claims: Carl and Elizabeth Herz, 1949-1954 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 14)
  - Miscellaneous address lists, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 15)
  - Curriculum vitae, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 16)
  - Bibliography of published writings, 1931-2002 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 17)
  - Lists of publications, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 18)
  - Certificates of honors, awards, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 19)
    See also documents located in Oversize Box 30.
  - Course announcements, Howard University, 1941-1943 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 20)
  - Course listings, announcements, 1953-1962 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 21)
  - Course listings, City College of New York, 1968-1975 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 22)
  - Personal accounts, mostly, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 23)
  - Photographs (2), Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 24)
  - Miscellaneous personal materials, Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 25)
  - "Herz participates in Democracy". Undated autobiographical statement, ca. 1968 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 26)
  - Travel notes, 1973 August (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 27)
  - "My Visit to Korea and Japan, January 1974", Undated (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 28)
  - Photographs, International Symposium on Peace and Security, East Asia, 1974 January 21-1974 January 24 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 29)
  - Documents relating to Herz receiving Germany's Verdienstkreuz 1. Klasse, 1974 October 24 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 30)
  - Retirement dinner, 1977 April 22 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 31)
  - John H. Herz zum 70. Geburtstag. Festschrift, 1978 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 32)
  - Herz Festschrift contributions, letters of congratulation, 1978 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 33)
  - CUNY Graduate Center News Reports citing Herz' scholarly activities, 1978-1990 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 34)
  - Newspaper clippings about Herz, 1940-1994 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 35)
  - Newspaper clippings about Herz, 1997 September (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 36)
  - Newspaper clippings, 90th birthday, 1998 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 37)
  - Herz - Aschaffenburg Archive listing, Leo Baeck Institute, 1980-1993 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 38)
  - Elizabeth Aschaffenburg Herz. Last will, 1972 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 39)
  - Thekla Herz. Memoirs, 1928 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 40)
  - Interview about Herz' OSS activities, ca. 1980 (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 41)
  - "An Internationalist's Journey through the Century", 1988; Typescript (Box 1 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 42)
  - "Report on my trip to Germany (Frankfurt - Berlin), November 5-20, 1989", Undated; Typescript, correspondence (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 1)
  - From Swastika to Jim Crow. Transcript of a film in which Herz was featured, 1999 (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 2)
    Copy of video (in cold storage room).
  - From Swastika to Jim Crow. Newspaper clippings, 2000-2001 (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 3)
  - John H. Herz Award, City College, 2001 (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 4)
  - Restitution correspondence, documents, 2001 (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 5)
  - Michael Allen. "The Rational Surplus in a World of Kill or Perish: John Herz, Realist Liberalism and the Possibilities of Ethical Behavior in the Nuclear Age", 1981 December 20; Typescript (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 6)
  - Kurt Düwell. "Ossip K. Flechtheim und John H. Herz - fast parallele Lebensläufe", published version, 1998; Typescript (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 7)
  - Angela Genger. "Zusammenfassung des Gesprächs mit John (Hans) Herz am 14.3.1997 in Scarsdale, N.Y", Undated; Typescript (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 8)
  - Alfons Söllner. "Interview mit Prof. John Herz in New York am 30. November 1983", Undated; Typescript (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 9)
  - Peter Stirk. "John H. Herz and international order", 2005 April (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 10)
    Photocopies of published article.
  - "Lebensbericht. Eine Biographie meines Weltbildes". Early version of Vom Überleben pp. 1-106, 1983 April 26; Typescript (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 11)
  - "Lebensbericht. Eine Biographie meines Weltbildes", Undated; Typescript (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 12)
    pp. 107-193a.
  - "Lebensbericht. Eine Biographie meines Weltbildes", Undated; Typescript (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 13)
    pp. 194-299.
  - Vom Überleben. Wie mein Weltbild entstand, 1984 (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 14)
  - Vom Überleben. Wie mein Weltbild entstand, pp. 194-299, Undated; Typescript (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 15)
  - Vom Überleben. Register of persons (not printed in book), Undated (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 16)
    Card file.
  - Vom Überleben. Unbound printed copy with some corrections, Undated (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 17)
  - Vom Überleben. Notes, Undated (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 18)
  - Vom Überleben. Radio discussions, Undated (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 19)
  - Vom Überleben. Advertisements, Undated (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 20)
  - Vom Überleben. Reviews, Undated (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 21)
  - On Human Survival. How A World - View Emerged. Bound copies of English version of Vom Überleben, 1988 May (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 22)
  - On Human Survival, Undated; Typescript (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 23)
    Chapters 1-3.
  - On Human Survival, Undated; Typescript (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 24)
    Chapters 1-7.
  - On Human Survival, Undated; 155p (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 25)
  - On Human Survival, Undated; 188p (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 26)
  - On Human Survival, Undated (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 27)
    Miscellaneous pages, chapters.
  - Income Tax returns, 1940s-1950s (Box 2 (1-Biographical & autobiographical ), Folder 28)
- General correspondence, 1938-2005; 2; 124 file folders
  The general correspondence series contains correspondence with Herz's colleagues in the academic community, as well as personal correspondence, and includes lengthy exchanges with: Enno Bartels, Honoré Catudal Jr., Ernst Otto Czempiel, Ossip and Lili Flechtheim, Christian Hacke, Uwe Prell, Kenneth Thompson and Erich Wenderoth.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  - A - miscellaneous, Undated (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 1)
  - Wolfgang Abendroth, 1961; 1965 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 2)
  - Rolf Ahmann, 1986-1988 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 2)
  - Gabriel A. Almond, 1946; 1951; 1961; 1978 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 3)
  - Erich Angermann, 1960 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 3)
  - Joachim Arenth, 1989 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 3)
  - Sinclair Armstrong, 1950 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 3)
  - Karl Aschaffenburg, 1944; 1946 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 4)
  - Walter Aschaffenburg, 1977; 1993 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 4)
  - Max Ascoli, 1949 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 4)
  - B - miscellaneous, Undated (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 5)
  - Enno Bartels, 1980-2005 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 6)
  - Jewel Bellush, 1968; 1981; 1985; 1999 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 7)
  - Joseph W. Bendersky, 1978-1979 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 7)
  - Roger Benjamin, 1981 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 7)
  - André Bessler, 1990 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 7)
  - Hans A. Bethe, 1950 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Angelo Bolaffi, 1985 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 8)
  - Kenneth Booth, 2002-2005 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 9)
  - Edwin M. Borchard, 1938-1940 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Gerard Braunthal, 1969; 1993 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Max Brünn, 1938 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 10)
  - Franziska Buchegger, 1999 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Valerie J. Bunce, 1984 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 11)
  - Ralph J. Bunche, 1940; 1943; 1964 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 11)
  - C - miscellaneous, Undated (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 12)
  - Honoré (Marc) Catudal Jr., 1972-1988 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 13)
  - Sok Chough, 1973-1990 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 14)
  - Carl Q. Christol, 1987 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 15)
  - James B. Christoph, 1974 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 15)
  - Ernst Otto Czempiel, 1969-1971 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 16)
  - Ernst Otto Czempiel, 1972-1974 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 17)
  - Ernst Otto Czempiel, 1975-1988 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 18)
  - Ernst Otto Czempiel, 1989-2005 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 19)
  - D - miscellaneous, Undated (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 20)
  - John A. Davis, 1964; 1988; 1996 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 21)
  - Karl W. Deutsch, 1963; 1966 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 21)
  - Matthew Dever, 1981 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 21)
  - Alfred Diamant, 1978 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 22)
  - Joseph J. DioGuardi, 1985 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 22)
  - Walter L. Dorn, 1949 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 22)
  - Volker Dotterweich, 1980-1983 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 22)
  - Hans Drevermann, 1985 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 23)
  - Ivo Duchacek, 1974-1984 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 23)
  - Joseph Dunner, 1962-1963 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 23)
  - Kurt Düwell, 1997-1999 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 24)
  - E - miscellaneous, Undated (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 25)
  - Edward Mead Earle, 1940; 1951 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 26)
  - William Ebenstein, 1948 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 26)
  - Theodor Ebert, 1981-1982; 1998 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 27)
  - Henry W. Ehrmann, 1949 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 27)
  - Elliott Eisenberg, 1973 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 27)
  - Rainer Eisfeld, 1991-1992 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 28)
  - Salo Engel, 1962-1963 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 29)
  - Rainer Erd, 1980-1982 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 29)
  - Fritz Erler, 1959 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 29)
  - Richard Evers, 2002 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 29)
  - F - miscellaneous, Undated (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 30)
  - Richard A. Falk, 1966; 1971 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 31)
  - Christian Fenner, 1975; 1977 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 31)
  - Benjamin B. Ferencz, Undated (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 31)
  - W. H. Ferry, 1987-1988 (Box 3 (2-General correspondence), Folder 31)